A Guide to the Papers of the American Rhododendron Society
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #10553-af
Papers of the American Rhododendron Society ca. 1944-1948; 1965-1997
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
10553-af
ca. 600 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
This collection bears no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
These papers were given to the University of Virginia Library by the American Rhododendron Society through Sandra McDonald, Hampton, Virginia, on January 7, 1998.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of the American Rhododendron Society, ca. 600 items (3 Hollinger boxes), ca. 1944-1948, 1965-1997, consists of minutes, in files and an early bound volume; by-laws; additions to the Chapter Notebook; the correspondence and memoranda of President Austin C. Kennell, correspondence of Kennell and the Chapters, and correspondence of Kennell and the Executive Secretary, Barbara Hall; correspondence with the Editors of the
Journal of the American Rhododendron Society
, Adele Jones and Sonja Nelson; records of the search committee to fill the editor position; files pertaining to the executive secretary position and its duties; financial statements of the American Rhododendron Society and the Seed Exchange Fund; policies of the Board; membership census; scheduling of the National Conventions; a video cassette tape recording discussing the history of how the organization started, sent by William Robinson to Barbara Hall; and a file on the International Rhododendron Union.
Item Listing
- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1988-1997; (4 folders) (Box Box 1)
- By-laws (Updates), 1987-1996 (Box Box 1)
- Chapter Notebook, 1981-1982; (2 folders) (Box Box 1)
- Chapter Notebook, 1983-1985, n.d. (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence of President Austin C. Kennell, 1990-1991; (3 folders) (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence of President Austin C. Kennell with Chapters, 1989-1990 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence of President Austin C. Kennell & the Executive Secretary, Barbara Hall, 1989-1990 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence with Editor Adele Jones, ca. 1989-1990 (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence with Editor Sonja Nelson, 1990-1993; (2 folders) (Box Box 2)
- Correspondence with Editor Sonja Nelson, 1994 (Box Box 3)
- Editor Search Committee, 1990 (Box Box 3)
- Executive Secretary, 1989 (Box Box 3)
- Executive Secretary - Duties & Information, 1965-1990 (Box Box 3)
- Financial Statements, 1981-1994; (2 folders) (Box Box 3)
- Financial Statements - Seed Exchange Fund, 1986-1994 (Box Box 3)
- Foreign Exchange Rate, ca. 1986-1990 (Box Box 3)
- International Rhododendron Union, 1988-1996 (Box Box 3)
- Membership Census by Chapter, ca. 1978-1988 (Box Box 3)
- Memoranda of Austin C. Kennell, 1989-1990 (Box Box 3)
- National Convention Scheduling, Correspondence, 1983-1987 (Box Box 3)
- Policies of the Board, 1970, 1988-1996 (Box Box 3)
- American Rhododendron Society Meeting Minutes, with some additional material in the front of the volume, 1944-1948; Oversize Volume
- "Old Timers Discussing the Start of the Rhododendron Society in Portland, Oregon. Filmed at the home of Herb and Betty Spady near Salem." Mike Stewart, Past President of Portland Chapter, American Rhododendron Society, is the Master of Ceremonies, 1993 Jan; Videocassette Recording